ORIGINAL WORK BY TATSUYA ENDO
SERIALIZED ON SHUEISHA'S SHONEN JUMP PLUS
MISSION 23: THE UNSHAKEN PATH
The Phony team is on fire!
Take this!
Look at the trajectory of Carrol's ball!
Damn it! Onto the next plan!
Manipulate the height of the net!
-Twilight.
-I know.
The net's being altered
by a balls' length.
Recalculate the trajectory of the ball,
and keep striking back.
It's not working at all!
Then we'll use the wind!
Hey! It's being used against us instead!
Damn it!
The Campbell team used many tricks
to sabotage their opponent…
Spray the ball with a stinky substance!
The smell is killing us too!
But such tricks were just child's play
to the spy team who were on fire.
Your observation skills, judgment calls,
and control of the ball,
are all perfect, Nafalia.
I'm so glad you're on my team.
Darling…
This is the last set!
-Who will come out victorious?
-Damn it.
I wish this tournament would last forever.
Maybe I can maneuver the game
into an endless tiebreaker.
No, you can't do that Nightfall.
If you do that,
Twilight will end up despising you.
I was just reminded of the reason why
I respect this man so much.
I can't forget that.
It looks like Nightfall is strategizing.
She has regained her calm.
What is wrong with you two?
Do you know how much money is at stake?
Damn it.
We'll have to use our last resort.
They stopped using cheap tricks?
There it is. I got this.
A new signal?
Nafalia!
Twi…
Twain pounced on his wife all of a sudden
and they both fell over!
Hey, stop being all lovey-dovey
during a game.
Did they sense that they were
about to get shot? That can't be.
Darling! Darling, are you all right?
Don't worry. I'm not hurt at all.
Darling.
It's a special rubber bullet.
There's a sniper in the duct behind us.
Look, it's even painted in the same color
as the court.
I'm sorry. I should've been more alert.
Don't worry.
I thought this might happen,
so I wore a bulletproof vest.
You're amazing.
You're always thinking of
what might happen. You're awesome!
That can't be! He's not hurt?
It hit him, didn't it?
They've really crossed the line now.
If we bring it up,
maybe we can get them penalized.
Depending on where we got hit,
it could be fatal.
I wonder…
The staff members and management
are placed under their operation.
If by any chance,
this tournament gets disrupted,
and we lose our chance
at getting the painting,
that would really be fatal to us.
Thankfully, these bullets travel slowly.
If we purposely create an opening
and move quickly, we can evade the hits.
Don't miss their signals.
I will try.
Are you guys all right?
I'm sorry.
I'm still hungover from last night,
so my legs are a little stiff.
No way!
-Believe it or not.
-Just kidding.
Twain is playing brilliantly while dealing
with a hangover!
Let's resume the game.
He's aiming during the serve?
Twain is displaying some weird moves…
but what a serve!
Damn it, did I miss?
-Court maneuver team!
-Is he still hungover?
Let's synchronize and obstruct them.
We must make sure the Campbell kids win!
Roger!
Argh.
-Why can't I hit them?
-Moving very strangely.
Are they both hungover?
He's somewhat skilled
but that's why he's easy to read.
Team BB! We need your support!
Don't get caught by
the audience or the referee.
Number one, roger.
Number two, roger.
It's coming, Nightfall.
Yes, Twilight.
The ball boys are in it too?
Twain just struck the air!
He parried it?
Same here.
We have two more nuisances to deal with.
Yeah, but unlike the sniper who's hidden,
we can read their moves
by their eyes and fingers
so they're no big deal. Let's end this!
The Phony team is moving
every which way now!
Is this similar to what the east calls
the "Drunken Fist"?
Carrol and Kim, stop them!
You must defeat that pair!
Are you okay?
Yeah, no worries.
I drank some bad milk this morning.
Believe it or not, Carrol has been
playing while fighting stomach pains!
It's a battle of wills!
It's a heated match!
I don't want to lose!
I don't want to lose, but…
Our opponent is just too formidable!
Game, set and match!
The winner is the Phony team!
All right!
You saw right through all of our tricks,
didn't you?
And yet, you still defeated us.
We lost.
For the first time in my life,
I'm feeling so disappointed.
You're still young, and you have talent.
Train to fight fair and square.
You'll be a great player one day.
Mr. Twain, I will try my best
and work hard!
Good luck.
Not only do you accomplish your mission,
you also help to reform your opponent.
You're amazing, Twilight. I love you.
How idiotic.
They lost the game,
but they also gained something too.
My son has matured.
Do you know how much you lost?
Sir, you have a call.
Stop being a killjoy!
-I'm enjoying this moment right now.
-Well, the thing is…
Since the Phony team won,
they will be presented with an art piece
from Mr. Campbell's collection.
Congratulations!
This is it. I want "Lady in the Sun."
I understand.
-I will go get it from the gallery.
-Hold on a second.
I'm very sorry,
but I'm afraid we can't give you
that painting.
Why? It's even included in the catalog.
There has been a change of plans.
You may choose anything else,
and I'll even add something extra
as compensation.
-Twilight…
-It's just as expected.
He just got a call from
the state security service.
I think they received news about the code.
They'll come here to get that painting.
Well? You don't have to
make your decision right away.
If it's all right, may we take a look
at the collection first?
Sure, of course.
Wow, it's wonderful.
Not everyone can enter this room.
You're very lucky.
Where's your husband?
He's resting because of his hangover.
The painting is still here.
Do you have any recommendations?
If I can't get "Lady in the Sun,"
I'd like something other than a painting.
Let me show you.
-May I leave my luggage here?
-Of course.
Sir, what about "Lady in the Sun"?
They'll be here in ten minutes
to pick it up.
I told them to wait in the lobby,
so hurry up and get it out of here.
Yes, sir.
Hey, what are you doing? Hurry up!
I should check to make sure that
it's not damaged.
Don't worry about it.
It didn't seem like they cared much
about the artwork itself.
Yes, this is "Lady in the Sun."
Thank you for your cooperation.
I'm happy to help.
Let's continue working together.
Well,
I'll escort the Phony couple outside.
All right. Thanks.
While you're at it, ask them
if they want to play for me from now on.
Do you want to work here
in addition to WISE?
I don't want to play tennis for a while.
Well? What did you choose for our prize?
A strange vase
and he threw in some gaudy rings.
I don't want any of them.
Let's give them to Handler as a gift.
That sounds good.
I'm exhausted.
Everything went well.
Honestly, I panicked a little when he said
that he won't give it to us.
But it all worked out.
It's all thanks to you, for bringing
that forged painting in your bag.
It's all thanks to your disguise
and the quick switch.
It's a good thing the code was on
the painting and not the frame.
Yeah.
Traces of special ink used
in the back must be the code.
Let's hand it to the analytics team
right away.
The state security services will probably
continue looking for nonexistent
codes in "Lady in the Sun."
I bet.
At any rate,
our mission is accomplished!
Drop me off up ahead, Nightfall.
I'll drop you off at your house.
I want to be with you as long as possible.
I'm Loid Forger, a married man.
It won't be good if neighbors see us
and start suspecting things.
People have been reported
to the authorities for infidelity.
Twilight…
I was helpful with your
mission today, right?
I worked hard for you, Twilight.
I think I'm the perfect person
to be your partner.
Me…
I understand.
I'll see you at work.
Anya! Bond!
We have to go home soon!
Okay!
Yor and Anya were playing tennis
today too?
Nightfall!
Good evening, Mrs. Forger.
Oh, Fiona. Good evening.
It's that lady…
I'm back, Yor.
Hello, Loid.
She dropped me off on her way home.
I thought I'd stop and say hello.
I… I see.
You're playing tennis too?
Yes, Anya got hooked on it ever since
we practiced with Loid the other day.
Anya is good with home runs.
Thanks to that practice,
I did well in today's game.
Thanks.
I'm so glad.
Does she think that she helped
to level up his skills?
Where's the big prize?
You arrogant woman.
I can help him level up too… no…
I would have efficiently used
his strength to achieve greater things.
Then you must be good at
playing tennis too.
Can I ask you to play a game with me?
Hey Fiona, what are you saying?
I haven't had enough exercise today.
I WANT TO CHECK
AND SEE IF HER ATHLETIC ABILITIES
MEETS THE STANDARDS FOR OPERATION STRIX
Please play a game with me.
I will crush her!
I will completely and thoroughly
crush your heart,
and take away your place
in the Forger household.
I should've known my place.
I will forfeit the role of your wife
to Fiona.
-Okay!
-Huh?
Uh… Um…
I have no idea what's going on…
You don't have to force yourself.
I will take on your challenge!
I feel like I can't lose or run away
from this challenge!
I've always wanted to marry someone
who's good at tennis!
Are you serious? I'm super good.
Anya, did you see this week's episode
of "Berlint in Love"?
There was so much drama!
The main character's fiancée and
his childhood friend came face to face.
It was a fierce battle between two women.
Anya prefers anime.
Right now, Anya finally understands
how Becky feels!
Anya loves stories about battles too!
Come at me with all you've got.
Stop it, Fiona.
Stay out of this, Dr. Forger.
She's right.
It would be rude
if I played half-heartedly.
I will use all my strength!
Oh…
I'm disappointed in you, Yor Briar.
You're nothing but a… Hm?
Oh no, I did it again!
When I use too much strength,
the ball goes through the racket
and falls apart.
I'm sorry, Mr. Ball.
I'm so bad at playing tennis.
I must control my strength
so that the ball will fly.
Anya, do you have another ball?
Deliver the ball, logistics officer Bond!
-I'm sorry, I'll do it right this time!
-Wait…
What did I just see?
Did the ball disintegrate?
What?
It's faster than the speed of sound.
The trajectory of this ball is steadfast.
What a beautiful straight line.
It's totally out of bounds.
But who cares about that, Nightfall.
Place your racket in front of you.
Otherwise, you'll die!
It's so strong!
I can't push it forward!
But my love for Twilight
is just as strong!
This is nothing compared to
my feelings for him.
Forward! I must push my racket forward!
You must strike the ball
through Twilight's heart!
You can't let this woman have him!
Yes, in the future I'm the one who'll
be standing next to him.
We'll reminisce about our past
in the living room,
tour old battle fields together, and spend
our golden years in a neutral country.
Oh, just thinking about that
is getting me so excited.
So give me the title
of Mrs. Forger!
I lost… I totally lost.
I was thoroughly crushed.
That's why I told you to stop.
Are you okay? Are you hurt?
I'll admit it. Right now,
you're better than me.
What?
But someday…
I will challenge you once again.
Until that day comes,
go ahead and enjoy your nice life!
I will never give up!
Did I upset her?
That lady is full of life…
I think she's really passionate
about tennis.
I hope Yor isn't suspicious.
Well, this is just a marriage on paper,
so it doesn't matter…
Loid.
I won!
Uh… yes. Congratulations.
-I'm the winner!
-Yor, you're the winner!
I'm really exhausted.
Father, I'm hungry.
Sorry, can we order in today?
Good work on retrieving
that painting last week.
Let me fill you in on what we found.
Where's Nightfall?
She's holed up in the mountain today
to power up her swing.
I see.
The code itself was very simple.
We found out the coordinates
for the secret storage,
and sent our agents to retrieve it.
And where's the Zacharis Dossier?
A diary?
August 21st.
Today, I hid something dangerous
in the warehouse.
It's photographs of young actresses.
Huh?
I love musical performances.
I prefer comedic musicals
over tragic operas.
I especially love the ones
with young female actresses!
It makes me want to support them.
Huh?
I became so obsessed
that my wife beat me up one time.
How much money are you
spending on these things?
This is more like a donation…
One time I invited my wife to the theater,
but she didn't understand it.
Why do they start singing all of a sudden?
She told me to throw away
all of the pictures,
but I just couldn't get rid of
the rare photos.
From then on,
I started visiting the theaters in secret.
I hid everything
in the warehouse from the photos to
anything else that may reignite a fight.
So, the "reigniting of war"
is not between the East and West.
It's between him and his wife.
How in the world did this
become a secret document?
I worked hard just for this?
Just before the end of war,
when diplomats came from the West,
Colonel Zacharis took them
to a theater for a performance,
and told them to keep it a secret
so that it wouldn't get back to his wife.
Apparently, that fueled the rumors.
No, there must be another code
between the diary and the photos!
No. The analytics team checked
every inch of that thing.
There was nothing that would
reignite a war.
Let's take that as good news.
I guess you're right.
It's a picture of the Colonel.
"My wife and daughter whom I love."
At the end of the day,
he really loved his wife.
He kept peace with his wife,
by taking his secret to the grave.
No, if he really loved his wife,
he should've thrown it away. It's creepy.
You don't get it, do you?
They're two different things.
A rare item is a commodity!
A happy marriage is difficult to attain.
I'll take the apple tart,
and two pieces of
the caramel nut cake.
Here you go.
Here!
MISSION 24: MOTHER AND WIFE/
FRIENDS AND GROCERIES
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita